Finding aid for the Walter Jurmann papers, [1910]-1995 LSC.2271
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Series 2. Lyrics, 1966, undated
  - Subseries 1. Lyrics by Jurmann
    - I'm Stuck on the Guy (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - In Deinem Rosengarten (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - In Dich bin ich verliebt (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - It's One Year Tonight at Midnight (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - It's Up to You and Me (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Das Lament einer verliebten Frau (All I've Got is You on reverse) (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Long Live Israel (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Los Angeles, the City I Love (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Mein einziger Wunsch (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Mein schoenes Wien (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Never Say Goodbye to Me (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Nur eine Mutter versteht Deinen Schmerz (first line) (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Oh Donna Anna ([This is My Heart] on reverse) (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Ohne Erinnerungen (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - On the Bumpy Road to Romance (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Our Lovesong (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Our Love Will Live (Ohne Deine heiße Liebe on reverse) (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Please Don't Let Me Down ([These Are the Symptoms of Love] on reverse) (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Possessed (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - San Antonio (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - So lang Du noch träumen kannst (first line) (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Teach Me How to Love You (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - There Are So Many Islands (first line) (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - These Are the Symptoms of Love (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - This Is My Heart (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Unforgettable You (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Unvergesslich [Unforgettable You] (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Vergesse Deine Sorgen (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Vielen Dank (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Waiting (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Subseries 2. Lyrics by others
    The bulk is songs with Jurmann's music.
    - The American Way (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Cook with a Song (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - I Can't Take It Anymore (Lucky Lover on reverse) (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - If There Were Dreams for Sale (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Is It Really Love (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - It Had to Be (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - It Must Have Been Madness (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - It's Great to be a Soldier (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - I've Got Dish-pan Hands (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Little Tingle Tangle Toes (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Los Angeles/ Music by Walter Jurmann; Lyric by Arthur Hamilton (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Love is Here (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Lucky Lover (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - [Lucky Number] Drop a Penny in the Wishing Well (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Manhattan After Dark (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Mine (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Mulligan Stew (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - My Heart Ran Away with the Moon (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - New Love (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - On a Little Street in Nischninovgorod (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Say's the Bluebird (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - So Great My Love (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - The Tanks are Rolling Along (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - There Goes Another Day (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Well-Natch (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Whatever You Do Is Wrong (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Windmill in the Willows (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - You and the Waltz and I (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - You Don't Know the Meaning of Love (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Various (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Series 3. Business and personal papers, 1923-1978
  Series contains legal documents, which include contracts, agreements, and certificates of copyright relating to Jurmann's musical compositions. Also present are U.S., Austrian, and French passports and identity cards and international drivers permits; U.S. army records; honorary citizen and member certificates; and notes.
  Scripts, screenplays, plot synopses, lyrics, and other material relating to Jurmann's film and theater work, especially the musical Windy City, are also included.
  - Notes, Undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Legal documents, 1942-1973 (Box 4, Folder 7-8)
  - Identity records, 1923-1971 (Box 4, Folder 9-10)
  - U.S. Army records, 1943-1944 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Honors, 1967-1968 (Box 12)
  - Scripts
    The scripts, drafts, outlines, and lyrics for the musical Windy City (screenplay/story by Philip Yordan, lyrics by Pual Francis Webster, music by Jurmann) also include its other titles The Honest Gambler, Danny Boy, Heads or Tails, and Of Him and Her.
    - Condemned to Live, by Arnold Phillips and Lawrence Goldman, from an original story by Ken Britton, Undated (Box 5, Folder 1-2)
    - Goodbye Angel! by John Kafka and Walter Jurmann, Undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Maskerade: ein Musical nach dem gleichnamigen Tonfilm, by Walter Reisch, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Metropolitan Saga, by Walter Jurmann and Anne Freelick, Undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - The Secret Singer, by Ann Watermann, 1934 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - The Secret Singer, by Walter Jurmann (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - The Third from the Left, by Ladislas Fodor (2 copies), Undated (Box 5, Folder 8-9)
    - Windy City, 1943-1955 (Box 5, Folder 10-13, Box 6, Folder 1-5)
- Series 4. Correspondence, 1913-1987
  Correspondence of Walter Jurmann, his wife Yvonne Jurmann, and between others primarily concerns Jurmann's songs San Francisco and San Antonio. Also present are copies and drafts of letters Jurmann sent to U.S. presidents with responses. Jurmann family postcards, most of which are photographic portraits, include those sent by Jurmann and his brother Otto as well as two sent by Jurmann' s father Norbert to the family of his brother-in-law, Rudolf Fischer.
  Correspondence regarding specific contracts are located with the legal documents in Series 2.
  - Walter Jurmann, 1938-1970 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Yvonne Jurmann, 1967-[1985], undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Regarding Walter Jurmann, 1934-1987 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Jurmann family postcards, 1913-1920, undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Series 5. Photographs, circa 1913-[1995]
  Primarily consists of photographs of Jurmann, his wife Yvonne Jurmann, and the Jurmann family. Also included are group photographs containing Jurmann, and a few images of other individuals, landscapes, and Jurmann's gravestone.
  The identification of persons of some photographs was presumably made by Yvonne Jurmann (in pencil on reverse). See Jurmann family postcards in Series 4 for further photos of the family. Negatives were created by UCLA's Music Library from images of existing photographs and other items in the collection.
  - Walter Jurmann, circa 1913-circa 1970 (Box 7, Folder 5-6)
  - Yvonne Jurmann, circa 1946-1970s (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Walter and Yvonne Jurmann, circa 1953-1971 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Jurmann family, circa 1913-1930s (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Group photographs, circa 1910-1960s (Box 7, Folder 10-11)
  - Others, 1916-circa 1960s (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Landscapes, circa 1920s-1930s (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Gravestone, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Negatives, [1995], undated (Box 7, Folder 15)
- Series 6. Biographic material, 1934-1995
  Consists of articles, newspaper clippings, and other material about Jurmann's music and career. Much of this material was collected by Jurmann's wife, Yvonne Jurmann, and concerns posthumous events or press. Many items are in German.
  - Articles, 1968-1983 (Box 6, Folder 6-10)
  - Lists of works and discographies, Undated (Box 6, Folder 11-13)
  - Radio and television programs, 1976-1987 (Box 8, Folder 1-5, Box 6, Folder 14-15)
    Consists of announcements, listings, scripts and production material relating to posthumous radio and television programs about Jurmann or featuring his music.
  - Programs, [1941]-1995 (Box 9, Folder 1-4)
    Programs are primarily for posthumous concerts and festivals. Several are for events in San Antonio (folder 4).
  - Clippings, 1934-1988 (Box 9, Folder 5-10)
    Most clippings are housed in disbound scrapbooks and primarily concern Jurmann's official city songs for Houston, San Antonio, and San Francisco.
  - Resolutions, [1984-1985] (Box 8, Folder 6)
    City resolutions regarding the songs San Antonio and San Francisco.
- Series 7. Sound recordings, 1978-1983, undated (Box 9, Box 8, Folder 7-13)
  Includes two German 33 1/3 LPs of Jurmann's songs (box 9); 45s of the songs A Better World to Live In, Houston, San Antonio (English and Spanish versions), and Wien ist wieder Wien/ Mein schönes Wien (box 8); and a German cassette Autoren Porträts Walter Jurmann (box 8).
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  RESTRICTED ACCESS: Use of audio material requires production of listening copies.
- Series 8. Ephemera, 1967-1984
  - San Antonio tourism material, 1978, 1980s (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Man of Montmartre by Stephen and Ethel Longstreet (book, galley proofs), Undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Jurmann promotional ephemera
    Primarily consists of press releases, promotional ephemera, and graphic design layouts pertaining to Jurmann's official city songs for Houston, San Antonio, and San Francisco. Also included is an autographed poster for a posthumous concert of Jurmann's music.
    - Press releases and ephemera, 1967-1984, undated (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Graphics, Undated (Box 12)
    - Poster (Box 12)